Tell me. Why did you save me?
Don't know. Guess I really
didn't have a reason.
I'm the one who killed
your comrades on that airship.
I'm the one who crushed that
guard's skull with a brick.
Falco didn't do anything.
So kill me, not him. Okay?
We won't kill you.
Why not?
I know you must want to.
Why would I want that?
Always with the killing.
It's like it's all you ever think about.
Just like someone else I know.
Er...
I just wanna talk to you.
More conflict isn't necessary
to solve Eldia's problems.
Hange and the others are fine.
We're just relocating them.
Eren, Mikasa and I have been
wanting to talk to you, too.
What were you thinking when you decided
to attack Marley on your own?
Why do all this?
Did Zeke and Yelena really
win you over to their side?
I am free, Armin.
Every single thing that
I've done, I decided to do.
My actions are governed by
nothing but my own free will.
So even though you
secretly met with Yelena,
you're saying that this was all you?
Yes.
No way. You're being
manipulated!
The Eren I know would never involve
civilians and children in a war,
even if they were enemies.
And you wouldn't put us at risk either.
You care about us more than anyone.
Don't you?
You rescued me from those
kidnappers in the cabin
and wrapped this scarf around me,
because you're a kind person!
I said to keep your hands
on the table, Mikasa.
Back in Liberio, I spoke with Zeke,
brother to brother.
Learned a lot of things from him.
Honestly, it seems like
he knows even more
about how Titans work than Marley does.
Armin, What do you think it is
that drove you to start visiting Annie?
Do you really believe
it's your own free will?
Huh? What? I don't...
If memories play
a major role in shaping us
into the people we are,
then part of you has become Bertholdt.
Within you is an enemy who has
feelings for another enemy.
Understand?
Bertholdt has gotten into your head.
You're the one being
manipulated by the enemy.
Hey! Why would you...?
You're being controlled, too.
The Ackermann clan was
designed to be perfect
for the task of protecting Eldia's king.
Your Ackermann instincts were dormant,
until, in that life-or-death situation,
you heard me
order you to "fight."
The strength and certainty you felt
in that moment were awakened
because your blood mistook me
for the host you were made to protect.
That can't be.
It can't? Why not?
It wasn't a mistake.
It's because it was you.
It had to be you.
You're why I became strong.
How could that be a mistake?
As an Ackermann with awakened powers,
you're apparently supposed to
get headaches pretty frequently.
The research said this is a side-effect
of the Ackermann's
true self trying to resist
being forced to protect their host.
Sound familiar?
You're wrong.
What I'm saying is...
No. I...
You belong to a clan
created to protect and obey
at the cost of losing their true selves.
In other words: Slaves.
Stop! Leave her alone!
Do you wanna know what I hate
more than anything else in this world?
Anyone who isn't free.
They're no better than cattle.
Eren!
The mere sight of you has
always made me so damn angry.
And now I finally know why.
I just couldn't stand to look at
a slave with no mind of her own,
who always followed orders
without question.
Believe me when I say this, Mikasa.
Ever since I was a kid, I've hated you.
Eren! How could you
say that to her?
Mikasa?
See? Everything that
you've done in your life
has been dictated by
your Ackermann blood.
No. I... I was just...
That blood is all you really are.
Jaeger!
I don't need help.
Hey. Armin.
The two of us've never actually
fought before, have we?
You wanna know why that is?
It's because...
it'd never be a fair fight!
Please. Just stop.
Like I said at the start.
Conflict isn't necessary.
At least not if you
tell us where Zeke is.
So just come along
quietly. Take 'em.
Yes, sir.
And bring the kid who killed Sasha, too.
So that's it? That's all
you came here to say?
Is this the freedom you wanted?
The freedom to hurt Mikasa?
You're a slave, too.
And your master is a worthless bastard.
Who are you callin'
a slave? Let's go.
Go where?
The place where it
all started. Shiganshina.
It's not even funny.
The piece of shit
we need to feed to a Titan
is right beneath us.
What do you mean?
We'll transfer Zeke's
Beast to some other host.
We just need to grab someone expendable,
like one of these Jaegerists.
Turn them, then feed them Zeke.
I don't know if Eren's
under Zeke's control or not,
but I do know that if
the Jaegerists lose Zeke,
their party's over.
Go tell that
to Pyxis. All right?
Are you serious, Captain?
Tell him I'm about to
cut Zeke's limbs off.
That should get him moving.
But...!
Enjoying your book?
As much as possible, for a book
I've read seven times.
Seems to me that you've
been eavesdropping
more than you've been reading.
Can you really blame me when I've
read the book this many times?
By the way, is there any wine left?
Of course not, we've been here a month.
There isn't a single drop left.
Damn, too bad.
You're a real expert
torturer, ya know that?
Just read your book.
As you command, Captain.
I'm chopping him up
no matter what Pyxis says.
We have 30 fully-armed soldiers
waiting in the trees up above.
Even if Zeke becomes the Beast,
there's no way he'll escape.
That bearded piece of
shit was our enemy after all.
Now that we know that,
he's just a hostage.
And hostages don't need limbs.
It took long enough. Erwin.
I can finally make good on
the promise I made you.
There was meaning in your deaths.
At last. I can prove it.
Hey.
Whoa. What was that?
My body went numb for a second.
So did mine.
Huh? I didn't feel a thing.
What's the matter?
I feel like I just got
shocked by electricity.
Wait, does that mean...?
Zeke's done it, hasn't he?
This is goodbye, Captain.
You're a caring leader.
And your soldiers haven't
done anything wrong.
You wouldn't slice 'em up
just 'cause they've grown
a bit, now would you?
Wine?
Why would we bring wine on a mission?
Please, Captain!
This is rare Marleyan wine!
The MPs have been hoarding
most of it for themselves!
Don't we deserve a treat, too?
We've got tea.
Captain!
Gimme a break. Fine. Bring it.
Shit. Zeke's spinal fluid
was in the wine? Since when?
Not a single person
froze up! Was it all a lie?
Damn it. They're fast.
How are they able to move like this?
Is that because of Zeke, too?
Varis.
Are you still somewhere in there?
You guys.
It's too bad.
In the end, we couldn't trust each other.
Before long, all the world's might
will fall upon this island.
You could never comprehend
what that means.
After the raid on Liberio,
you thought that you had
power, time, and options
to choose between,
but the truth is that
you had none of those.
And that led to your downfall.
Still, even if I'd
explained my intentions,
you wouldn't have understood.
Right, Eren?
Only we understand.
Once I'm out of this forest,
I'll be with you in no time.
I'm worried.
You do remember when and where
we agreed to meet. Right?
Kill him!
Huh? Come on, not again!
Damn it! What the hell
are you made of?
Where did you go?
Come on out, Levi! Fight me!
There you are.
Where did all your cute
little soldier friends go?
Don't tell me you killed
'em all! The poor things!
A branch?
You look desperate, hairball.
All you had to do was
read your damn book.
What gave you the idea
that you could escape from me?
If you really thought I'd hesitate to
kill my comrades once you turned them,
then you have no idea how
many friends I've had to kill.
Ah. Hey, Beardy.
Amazing. You've gotten
uglier somehow.
You even smell worse. Shitbag.
Well, don't worry.
I'm not gonna kill you. Not yet.
As you know,
Premier Zachary's assassination
has destabilized the military
and the general state of
affairs within the walls.
However. That has nothing
to do with you cadets.
Which is why the 109th Cadet Corps
will practice defending
Shiganshina District
from Titan attack, just as planned.
Do you hear me?
Uh. Yes, sir!
Glad to hear it, Cadet...
Why are we still being taught how to
cut a Titan's nape with a blade?
It's not like they'll attack again.
Our enemies are all human now.
My old man was saying the same thing.
He thinks we should train with firearms
and form a new Eldian army.
It's all too obvious
that the times have changed,
but Commandant Shadis
is stuck in the past.
If there's any hope for Eldia's future,
it's in the Jaegerists
taking power by force.
Stop, Surma. He'll hear you.
So what? You all
feel the same, right?
I'm sure that everyone here
wants Eren Jaeger to lead Eldia.
We need a strong, capable leader
who can make hard decisions.
Hange?
Long time no see, Commandant.
Sorry to interrupt,
but we'll be occupying
this facility for a while.
As you may have heard,
we're a group known as the Jaegerists.
And if you don't wanna die,
you'll follow our
instructions to the letter.
It's the Jaegerists.
Congratulations, you finally figured out
where you stand, Floch.
No one gives a damn about your gang.
There's only one way
you can get our attention.
That's to grab a bunch of guns
and start waving them around.
How long did...
What's with you?
Barely missed. I figured
I could speed things up
by shooting the Commandant in the foot.
What do you want from me?
Nothing. This isn't about you.
Our movement doesn't have any use for
old men with hard heads and little else.
Listen, Cadets. Starting
right now, this is your time!
Eldia's in grave danger,
but we Jaegerists
are doing everything
we can to protect her.
We've pledged our hearts and souls!
We are fighting.
Not for the fossils in
command of our military,
but for the people of
the island we call home.
If you keep complying with the
archaic mindset of our leaders,
then the day will soon come
when you're forced to
watch helplessly as our enemies crush us!
So I ask each of you this:
Who would you rather be?
Someone who lives to see the future
alongside Eren Jaeger,
the leader of Eldia?
Or someone who dies,
alongside Commandant Keith Shadis
and the antiquated ways of the past.
For the sake of Eldia's
future, we dedicate our hearts!
That's good.
But now I need to see you
demonstrate your resolve.
I want you to beat up
the Commandant here mercilessly
until he can't stand anymore.
What?
He represents the obsolete traditions
that we need to do away with.
So purge him at once!
Anyone who refuses will be detained!
Come on, this is ridiculous!
You've made your point, Floch!
Hange!
No matter how many of
these weak brats come at me,
there won't be nearly enough!
Well done.
We're delighted to welcome each of you.
Now then. If it's
not too inconvenient,
guide us to where Zeke's being held.
Commander Hange.
Hey. Let's go.
Are you awake?
Hey. Stop that. No sudden moves.
I stuck a thunder spear in your gut,
and attached the fuse to the
wire wrapped around your neck.
Squirm too much and you'll be
blown in half. At least.
I bet you wish you were dead right now.
Not that I sympathize. Bastard.
You used my comrades like cheap toys.
When you planned this,
did you think you'd end up here?
Sobbing into your own filth?
Shut your mouth.
I have no choice but to
hack you into pieces.
If I don't, you'll turn
into a Titan again!
Hey, Levi. Where are my glasses?
Huh? What's it matter?
You don't have any need
for glasses anymore.
Whoa. Nice one, Zeke!
You're gettin' to be a proper pitcher.
Ever think about playing ball
when you grow up?
I'm sorry, but I can't,
Mr. Ksaver.
I have a mission.
He summons up long-missed faces,
and memories from his faded past.
With them comes a reminder
of what he must do to
achieve his mission.
Next episode: "Sole Salvation."